<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-exercise-tips</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-08-31/ed-1/?sp=25</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> Rolling A Barrel For Health
	THE latest fad in the line of
physical culture Is barrel
rolling. Nowadays both men
and women may be found
who daily make It a duty to
exercise for a certain length
of time with a common, everyday barrel.
Corpulent people may now rejoice, for
this latest acquisition to the catalogue of
health and figure improvement methods
has been proven to do everything claimed
for it.
Thin, sickly people may also join th*
chorus, for it not only reduces flesh with
fleshy individuals, but makes flesh atd
muscle. Improves the breathing apparatus,
invigorates the action of the heart and
brings about a graceful carriage.
All the properties needed consist of ,a
small barrel or keg. The exercise may
be taken in a bedroom, although out of
doors is better.
Barrel-rolling, like all other kinds of
exercise, must be taken In regulated!
doses. The man who goes at It like ha
woulJ to a fire will realize little real bene
fit He will derive the greatest who
makes it a business as well as a pleas
ure, begins on a small scale and works up
to his greatest capacity gradually and
naturally.
The exercises given in the following are
prepared especially for those who are
earnest erough to have a try with this
new method and who will be really con-
scientious in their work.
For the first exercise the barrel Is laid
on the floor on its rolling surface.' The
body should be so arranged that only the
tips of the fingers and the palms of the
hands touch the floor, the greater weight
of the body ing borne by the keg. The
body should then be propelled forward,
the hands being used for that, purpose.
The legs and arms must be kept as rigid
'as possible, and the feet must not be
moved until the barrel, moving naturally
downward, reaches the knee. Now re
verse the movement, pushing backward
with the hands until the barrel is rolled
up to the arms. This exercise should be
repeated several times. It is the most
important of all for reducing the weight,
although It tends equally with the fol
lowing, others to develop the arms,
broaden the chest and make the abdom
inal muscles flexible.
The second exercise Is practically the
reverse of the.first. Rest with the back
en the cask this time. Place the arms
downward, and rest the heels on the floor
—the heels only, mind; no other part of
the legs. In order to get the barrel in
motion, move the arms alternately as far
forward as possible. The cask will then
reach the heels, the body being raised
from the floor. As before, reverse this
movement and "bring the cask up to the
small of the back, still taking care to
keep the legs stretched out straight.
"While performing this exercise, keep the
lungs well filled, the stomach drawn in
and the chest expanded. When the keg
is up to the part of the back referred to
lift th* arms from the floor and extend
them along the side of the body.* with
open palms on hip. Keep this position as
long 1 as possible without strain.
The third exercise is a pretty one. It
la performed by lying with the left side
of the body, just above the hip, resting
'on the" barrel. If you wonder why, in the
picture, the right hand is upraised, you
will know as soon as you begin the exer
cise. vlt is to balance the body, for the
feet qnly touch the floor. "With your left
hand pull your body forward as far as
possible until the feet can be raised from
the floor. This is not as easy as it looks,
but a little perseverance will manage it.
Then move back to the former position.
.When this exercise has been fairly well
jnnEtered, repeat it. but by lying on the
richt side of the body and holding the
hft hand in the air. This exercise is
liable \to strain the body if it is perse
vered In with too much zeal, and care
should, therefore, be taken to be conser
vative.
The fourth movement consists of lying
with the back on the cask, the arms, at
first, folded. This, while appearing to be
similar to exercise number two, is quite
rent, for here the feet only are U3ed
to force the body over the barrel until
the latter has reached the shoulders anl
back of the head, when the arms are then
placed at the side, as in the illustration.
As in the second exercise, do not neglect,
while in this position, to keep the stom
ach drawn in and the chest expanded. No
person with a weak back should prac
tice this movement, for the strain upon
the neck is rather severe, and an acci
dent might be attended with unpleasant
consequences.
The fifth is a fine exercise, easy, grace
ful and at the same time beneficial. Stand
straight up, with the feet together, stom
ach in. chest out, shoulders square, and
head back. Place the small barrel first
upon the toes. Bend down and grasp hold
of it. and bring it, not too quickly, up to
the waist line and thence above the head.
Hold it there for a second or two, being
sure that your figure is perfectly
straight. !V
A good method of regulating the breath
ing apparatus, the functions of which are
rather severely drawn upon in this exer
cise, is to count, one, two, three, four,
etc., at each swing-up of the cask, and
inhale air through the nostrils only at
the even numbers, two, four, six, and so
on.
The sixth exercise follows naturally
from the fifth. Raise the cask from the
toes to the chin line, still keeping the
body rigid, though the legs may bo
stretched a trifle apart, to preserve the
equilibrium, and swing the barrel to the
right and the left alternately. Follow
the same rules about breathing as in the
preceding movement.
The next exercise, the seventh, is one
which can be done expertly only by the
man who has Indulged in this form of
barrel-rolling exercise for some time, but
so many parts of the body are brought 
into play during It that nothing should
be neglected to bring one's salf to the
pitch of necessary ability. Stretch the
legs so that the feet are apart about
twenty-four inches. Then swing the bar
rel down briskly between the legs and
Tiigh up over the head, bending the back
and allowing the knees to bend slightly
forward as the barrel passes under the
body.
Go slowly about this exercise, for It is,
as has been intimated, no small strain
over the whole of the body, and it is not
one to be performed by the weakling. Yet
the weakling can easily get to it by prac
ticing the previous exercises. It is a
matter only of degree. Keep the lungs
partly filled as you exhale, because it la
neceesary to use the thoracic and ab
dominal muscles, for the Improvement of
which this exercise has been partly de
signed.
The cask ls placed In a novel position
for the eighth exercise—as far a? the
body Is concerned. That Is. one must re
cline upon it stretched lengthwise in the
tame direction as the body. Place th?
hands on the floor In front and let the
toes, the tips of which touch the ground,
support your legs.
Now roll from left to right, or the bar
rel from right to left, according to the
way of looking at It. Refrain from be
coming too enthusiastic at this pastime,
or the barrel will slip away from under
you and you may flatten your face
against the surface of the floor or
ground.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045396/1906-06-24/ed-1/?sp=25</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>How to Make The Most Of Your Vacation (text is fudged due to bad scanning)
no better panacea for ills, real I
supposed, than judicious exercise J
a the open.
I Growing girk and -women living
to'ns or closely confined in city of
.fctt should endeavor to obtain
in the open air aa possible, and to
wmmer sports during their holidaya
'"Wj anemic, undersized, under-wcigiit-,"ou(5
cornea are the ones that most
wre'.B mapc healing.
Riificient exercise tho Bvstem becomes
the Utah Boft and flabby, the skin
Tinkled, the muscles lax and easily
iitS D m1,ow" and one's whole being
d it v"n( anbition on account of the
ffiWj laws.
u f outdoor exercise ib cultivated
f "npoaiblc to give it up. Even in
bil Birls rcul lar8c hnlla for lcn'
U iT muncles wll not become lax and
itg firmness.
OUTDOOR EXERCISE A HABIT
I rcgUrd exercise in the open light
it tlft game or croquet or walk a
WJiMl are dcad tire(1- noor thj6s
tilt Untii tue' Rtir un a Healthy
1 educes vigor and energy by cor-
ka 0r narrow-chested, others have
.-MVt r Slr l P Incasurcinent is deficient
W'tat defects, too, but never
m 7 be cured, and a splendid mimcular
-e'
i
development induced by exercise bet fitted ior
individual requirements.
And when the caves begin to turn in tnc au
E artificial beautifies arc no more. Ihe
fcSfhy Sow on check, the sparkle of her eye,
he natural sheen of her locks, her broadened
ehea lar arms and limb, arc the souvenir
of her healthy, natural life in the open.
H around exercise is capital; no one will din
put c that, but it is possible that certain parts
of your anatomy require further development,
thai may be pained by certain forms of exercise
that bring muscles into play.
For example, swimming develops the rniiFclc
of the chest, arms, limbs, and abdomen, but its
greatest benefit lies in its powcrB of increasing
the circulation through reactionary causes. Row
ing, also brings into active condition both nius-J
cle aud blood.
Tennis is a diversion more likely to bo within
reach of the average city bred girl than any
other, lln's will develop tho muscles of her
arms, particularly the forearm, to a surprising
extent. -But here let nic whisper a note of warn
ing; play with both hands, or the one that wicldi
the racquet will cause the left arm to have th
appearance of being lop-sided.
When a girl is ambidextrous she can keep tho
development of both t-ides equal. And though
it may be tedious and uninteresting for a good
player to start all over again by playing villi tbu
left hand, it is worth all the trouble in the end.
In golf both hauda are used, and the mighty
swings not only stretch the musclcn of the arms,
but the chest and back as well. Add to this tho
benefit of walking over tho links.
Horseback riding is a most excellent form of
exercise, advised by doctors and physical cultu
rists alike.
It brings into play all the muscles, Fends the
blood thundering through the veins aud assured
ly gives a woman self-confidence, self-control as
Hi'do issues. A couple of months' riding will do,
more -to' develop the bust than a year of massaging-
Your bones will ache and your muscles vnll be
eore,' but cheer up. Any kind of exercise taken
when you are uuaccustdmcd to it will produce
imilar results.
The benefits of walking arc well known. This,
the most common form of exercise, is recommend
ed for fleshy people who wish to part with their
superfluous flesh, but the lean kind need not
worry- When walking is not too strenuously a
plied it is a most excellent all around exercise,
made doubly beneficial when the practice of cor
rect breathing becomes a part of your regime.
Remember that your exercise in the fresh air j
will have but little value unless you. take deep 'j
vitalizing breaths', filling your lungs to their ca- !i
pacity.
	</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1906-11-25/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EXERCISES TO KEEP THE FEET WARM
M"^^ ANY women in winter suffer habitually
from cold feet.
■pets This is not a vulgar slangism, if you
luaßsl I please, but an undesirable physical
condition, known also to men.
Nine times out of ten women so af
flicted hold sedentary positions, where there is
little chance for exercise, and as the average wo
man is too tired at night to walk a dozen squares
after dinner, she goes to bed with cold extremi
ties.
All the inner Roles, woolen hosiery nnd pee
per sprinkled in the bottom of trie shoes will not
temporary relief.
The only way to effect its cure is to Ect right
down to the seat of the trouble, to improper cir
culation, the bane of ho many women's troubles.
Besides the acute annoyance of having cold feet
this condition indicates that you ore not in good
health, that your constitution has become weak
ened, that your heart is none too strong and that
in consequence tlm circulation is languid.
And what some women would consider the
"unkindest cut of all," i* that a clear, unblem
ished complexion is absolutely impossible with a
sluggish circulation.
Nothing that fifty doctors can give you will so
materially help you as the following exercises,
which draw tlie blood to the feet and stir up an
all around good circulation.
If you are a chilly, bloodless creature ilon't
pamper yourself and keep close to the fireside.
No mutter how cold the day, j;o out and take an
airing, and walk, walk, miles if you can. Breatne
deeply as you go, holding your breath until you
count 25, then slowly exhale. Throw your
shoulders bad-, chest out, abdomen in; there you
have the correct position. Learn to make cor
rect breathing habitual.
Sleep in a well ventilated room. There is noth
ing worse for your health than a stuffy, ill-venti
lated room in which to sleep. Eat only whole-
some food and be sure to include such necessary
things in your diet us fresh fruits, olive oil with
your meals and after them, with grt^s juice whe
taken as a tonic, and distilled water.
EXERCISE I.
Place lice's together, toes apart, take a deep
breath. Then raiie heels from the floor as high
us you can. standing on tiptoe. Repeat £he ac
tion witlioir taking hold of any object; and so
continue as long as possible, without making
your muscles too tired,
Do it ten times if you can. Of course, it will
make the muscles of your limbs tired, but it soon
wears off. Increase the nuiuber of times at every
exercise and you will soon get up to 25.
I sure to take deep, full breaths while doing the
exercise.
EXERCISE 11.
Standing in the same position put your weight
on the heels and raise toes. Repeat, breathing
deeply.
EXERCISE 111.
Women who are afflicted with any organic dis
ease, especially heart trouble, should only take
up the following exercise under the supervision j
of a physical culture teacher or doctor.
Take correct position, heels together, toes'
apart, hands on hips. Take a full deep breath.
Now you arc required to do a funny little stunt-
Stnrt on a run, but stand just wnere you ore
lienil you kners far forward, then put left foot
out in front, then right. Repeat exercise without
allowing the herl.« to reneh the floor. Hold the
breath for a second, expel. Continue the motion
Until you fen] tired, rest, and resume it.
EXERCISK IV.
Place both hands over the head, locking the
thumbs together. Take a deep breath, rsieiug
your chest hign, and walk about yoxir room on
tiptoe; hold the breath for a few neconds, eipel,
take another, hold, expel; and bo walk about the
apartment until you are quite tired. Be sure to
keep your arms stretched high above your head.
When it possible to do thia exercise during
the day besides morning and night, so much the
better.
EXERCISE V.
Lie on the floor or on a very hard couch; for
in this exercise there must be no yielding under
the body. Take a deep inhalation through the
nose, raising the abdomen as you do so. Then
still holding the breath, force the chest upwards,
letting the abdomen down. Repeat movements,
and exhale through your nose while the chest is
raised. Practice until capable of doing move
ments five times without letting your breath out,
abdomen nnd chest up alternately.
EXERCISE VI.
Here ia another good exercise taken recum
bent position, lie on the floor, take a deep
breath, raißO the abdomen and feet without bend
ing tbe knees. When they are nearly perpendic
ular, bend knees and move limbs as though mov-
tag Ihe pedals of n bicycle. Be careful to turn
tile toes up and down an you mnke the revolu
tions. Continue for a minute then rent, Bnd con
tinue agnin, taking full inhalation* while exer
cising.
EXERCISK VH.
Stand erect, take a deep breath. Bend knee of
right limb and try to touch shoulder with it. D
thin ten times, breathing, holding breath, and ex
pelling; then take up exercise with left limb.
There is considerable work attached to these
exercises and some may be considered vigorous;
but they will certainly do the work for you if
faithfully followed.
For invalids and elderly people T should advise
having the feet and ankles rubbed and kneaded
with the bare hand, another's hnnds are bent;
they will impart new strength. Press the hands
against the iect ju»t as hard as the patient can
stand, do this for fifteen minutes a short time
before retiring. Just after a hot mustard bath
is good. A good cold cream bein^ used occasion
ally in place of the bare harirlc
	</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-07-28/ed-1/?sp=38</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EXERCISE FOR GIRLS
T* I IIERK is no disputing the fact that
girls need exercise as much as boys,
and the day has long gone by when
I a frail, delicate, white-faced girl
was regarded as being a model of
femininity.
Girls are no longer afraid of being strong
and ruddy They are beginning to thoroughly
understand that good health is not the pre
rogative of one sex, and that good health can
only Be preserved by exercise.
It is true that all girls cannot exercise as
they should. Some are so situated that ev
ery hour from sunrise to sunset has its duties,
each one confining; others inherit ailments
that prevent walking or running, and a few
perhaps are restrained by false ideas oi
dtcorum from developing their frames by ex
ercise. But the majority remain in a state
of ill health simply because they will not ex
ercise, or do not know how to set about it.
Perhaps many do not know what exercise
really is. A carriage ride is not exercise,
neither is housework nor any exacting labor,
no matter how hard it may be. II that were
bo, the blacksmith would be the most long
lived of men; but statistics prove otherwise.
Gymnastics are not always exercise in the
true sense. No pennnncnt good can come of
¦winging clubs or dumb bells in a close
room, unless followed by a brisk walk and
a bath. Croquet is exercise, and lawn tennis
is best of all. But. neither •of these games
is beneficial if played for fashion's sake.
The girl who gets herself up in a "stun
ning" costume and plays for the effect on
the spectators, might as well be reading a
novel in the parlor. Loose clothing, com
mon sense shoes and an ardent desire to win
tin 1 game, are the requirements for exercise.
Mowing is another capita] exercise for girls,
if they can overcome their natural timidity;
and swimming is better sitll. It is not gen
erally known that girls swim more gracefully
than boys and learn quicker. Both these ex
ercises have an additional value in the fact
'that they may some time preserve life.
Pitching quoits is beneficial exercise, and
trains the eye and hand. Badminton, a vari
ation of the old game of battledore and shut
tle-cock, is a game which forces all the
muscles of the legs and arms into action,
nml puts the players into a glow of pleasura
ble excitement.
Where good roads abound, cycling is an
exercise timt is beneficial, if not carried to
excess. No girl should attempt to ride more
than twenty miles a day: to ride more is re
ducing exercise to work. It is injurious to
try to pee how far or fast you can go in a
given time. Take it moderately and you will
?ever tire of your wheel.
Lastly comes walking, and I think that is
the ben( exercise of all. •It is the simplest
of all exercises, yet there are some rules to
be observed if you would get the greatest
bnefit. The best time to walk is before nine
in the morning or after five in the after
noon. Begin with a mile walk every morn
ing or evening and increase the length until
you can cover ten miles a day?
Walk in the country if possible; if that is
impracticable, choose wide streets, those nneci
with trees preferred. Mind how you walk.
Square your shoulders, expand your chest,
and hold your head high. Keep the mouth
closed when not talking, and breathe through
the nose. Step out easily and firmly, letting
the ball of the foot strike the ground first.
Vary the location of the walk each day if
possible, and exercise the ere and mind as
well as the body. Never let the walk become
a drudgery.
When you return home take a Rponge bath,
a vigorous rubbing, a cool gown, a glass of
milk and a nap. If you do not feel healthy,
happy and wise after a month of this exer
cise, you may be sure that yoii have some
chronic disease.
In summing up, remember that all exer
cise, to be beneficial, must be taken in the
open air. You may amuse yourself over a
billiard table or a game of cards, or you may
have a lovely time in a ball room, but you
cannpt develop your form or add an ounce to
your weight unless you breathe fresh air.
The simplest exercise in the open air will do
you more good than the most elaborate gym
naßtics"in a closed room.
You must also bear \p mind that exercise
must be continuous to be beneficial. Once
you get yourself in good condition, you must
keep there by constant exercise.
Do not look upon this as a task: with in
creaaing strength the exercise will be a posi
tive pleasure, which you will not think of
shirking. You will be proud of your ability,
arid your ambition will grow with your
achievements. Try it for one year, and see
if I am not a true prophet.
	</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1911-12-31/ed-1/?sp=21</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>How to Keep Fit
An indoor exercise that will help
to keep you ''flt" Is the imaginary
motion of lifting a piano, and the
other of drawing a cork from a bot
tle. Hold the bottle between your
knees and pull and pull at the
tightly driven cork. Both of these
contract the muscles of the abdo
men.whlch In most women are flac
cid and fall, giving them a balloony
appearance. Another exercise for
this purpose is to hold the knee
firmly by both hands, drawing It up
on a level with the waist Stand
thus for as long as you can. Then
shift to the other foot and repeat
exercise. This, like the two fore
going exercises, make tho mus
cles of the abdomen firm; form
lng a natural corset and giving
a naturally straight front Also
they reduce the hips.
walking and the exercises I
have described, combined with
deep breathing and the baths I
have mentioned, and plenty of
rest every woman knows how
long she must sleep to awaken
refreshed will keep her beauti
fully "fit"
	</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-10-25/ed-1/?sp=22</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1914-07-13/ed-2/?sp=8</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-01/ed-1/?sp=27</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-09-28/ed-1/?sp=13</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BETTERS THAN MEDICINE! 1915 BEAUTY SHOWS. STRETCHING EXERCISE FOR HEALTH
Exercise is "better than medicine. If
one would keep healthy. Better still
exercise brings beauty and grace. It's
the. best sort of tonic to keep the fig
ure from "sagging" or "settling" r
the dread of all women who care
about their appearance.
Exercise that gives the spine and
the abdominal muscles something to
do are best and America's famous
1915 beauty, Kay Laurell, of "Zieg
feld's Follies," is pictured in the ac
companying illustration in one posi
tion of a good stretching exercise.
To do this exercise lay- flat on the
back, and then keepingthe knees stiff
raise the legs to the position shown
in the Illustration. Hold for a count
of five, then lower and relax. Then
-repeat five times taking deep "stom
ach" breaths with the exercise.
</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020645/1904-12-11/ed-1/?sp=72</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE BEAUTY QUEST 
Exercises for the development of the arms, the shoulders and
THE CHEST—YOU MAY' REVERSE THE OLD SPANISH PROVERB IF YOU
CHOOSE.
Hear what the Spanish says "No
/woman under thirty has a beautiful
ihrm, and then she has ceased to care.’1
It Is very pessimistic, but worthj
of consideration. Reverse It and form
!/or yourselves another proverb: "The
[■woman under thirty may have a beau
jtlful arm and after that ahe may be
glad of one."
Nature, unaided. Is not often in
clined to round out an arm to Its full
[perfection In youth. Even a compar
atively stout girl is inclined to be
/Slender between wrist and shoulder.
(But exercise and massage will give
'the desired outline.
The exercises which you take for
arm development extend in their ben
leflcial effects to shoulders and chest,
thus rounding out the upper part of
(the figure and giving symmetry. It
would be Impossible, eveu if you wish
ed to Increase the arms alone by
[movements and leave the shoulders
/unaffected. Fortunately, no one cares
Co do so, for the "chesty" girl of the
/modern athletic life has come to stay.
«nd no matter how fashions change
'you will notice that her healthy vigor
‘remains the same—admired year in
land year out.
f A beautiful forearm is extremely
Irate, even though there be sufficient
‘/plumpness between shoulders. and el
bow. It should be well rounded at
(the elbow, from there taper down to
'a slender wrist. Most women have a
/forearm that is almost straight. It
books like a slat.
Indian clubs do more than anything
/else to develop this particular part
(of the arm. although their good work
‘does not cease there. They bring
Unto play the wrist muscles. They are
/twisted constantly, and this motion is
(made by the muscles of the lower
farm. When the broad savings of the
clubs are Introduced, then the shoul
V ders and other parts come In for their
^.a^are of the gain, but the twirling
Ss especially designed for the fore
arm muscles. Work with the clubs
(fifteen minutes at night and fifteen In
She morning.
I A simple exercise for the same part
cf the arm is this: Let the bacys of
the forearms rest upon the hips, draw
ing the elbows back so that the arms
Wich the hips near the wrists^ J 1“
hands are palms up. In this Poslt1'’"
clench and open the fists, spreading
the fingers as you do so.
To vary the monotony of this mo
tion. stretch the arms forward h°*‘:
sontally, palms down. Clench and
open the fists.
i For the upper arm. use this motion.
Raise the arms laterally until the el
hows are at shoulder level. Let the
'tips of the fingers rest lightly upon the
shoulders. Now force the elbows for
ward and backward as far as you can.
Drop the arms naturally against the
aides. Bring up the forearms against
l the chest until they stand vertically,
the edges of the palms forward, the
lingers straight and pointed upward.
Thrust the arms upward straight above
the head. To bring them back to the
‘original position, force them obliquely
«back and slowly let them fall to the
Bides again. Perform this exercise In
four counts: One, to raise the fore
arms: two, to thrust upward; three and
four, to let the arms fall.
An exercise used by Uncle Sam’s
Soys In blue is worth everything to
Jncle Sam's girls, as well, If they
•ould QU the hollows that lurk about
undeveloped shoulders. I^et the arms
fall at the sides. Raise them laterally,
palms up, and bring them to a grace
ful circle above the head, ending by let
ting the finger tips louch the top of the
head. The difficult part of this exer
cise Is to bring the backs of the fingers
against each other, while they meet on
top of the head, at the same time forc
ing the elbows back. When you have
learned to do this, forcing the elbows
back Into tje same plane as the body,
then It will be good for you to hold the
position for several seconds. You will
feel your chest forced forward under
the strain. To return, separate the
hands, turning the finger tips outward,
and let the arms describe a graceful
circle to the sides again.
A very old exercise, one used by
laborers to keep warm as well as by
women to round their shoulders, Is
simply swing the arms back and forth
outstretched, bringing the palms to
gether behind you as high as you can
make them reach.
A splendid shoulder exercise Is this:
Raise the arms laterally, palms up.
until they are at shoulder level. Keep
ing them outstretched, describe circles
with them, holding the palms always
up and never letting the arms pass In
front of the line of the breast.
Raise the elbows laterally to shoul
der level, letting the fingers rest light
ly upon the chest. Throw the arms
back until each entire arm Is out
stretched laterally, palms forward. You
must force them In such a way that
you can feel the chest pressed forward.
Raise the chest at the same time.
Let the arms fall at the sides. Raise
them laterally until the elbows are at
shoulder level, the finger tips resting
upon the shoulder, then let them fall
to the sides again. Do this lightly ten
times, then imagine a heavy weight
in the hands, and lift it powerfully to
the shoulder. Go through this ten
times.
Stretch the arms forward at should
er level, palms laid together. Separ
ate them, turning the palms down
ward, and move the arms back until
they are outstretched literally, still at
shoulder level. Let fall to the sides
slowly and repeat.
For the especial development of the
upper arm. resort to dumbbells. Al
most all of the elementary dumbbell
exercises have some effect upon this
part of the arm. The newer school
of extension work with dumbbells is
not devoted to this particular develop
ment, but the old-/ashioned exercises
are. for the most part, including? chest
and shoulder work. Do not use the
heavy Iron bell, however, as the old
school often prescribed. A two-pound
wooden bell Is best.</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1893-03-02/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93057084/1912-10-17/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1937-07-30/ed-1/?sp=21</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> 
Business women who sit at their
desks all day and have little oppor
tunity to exercise have more of a h;p
problem than women in the home, who
can get about if they like, play a
round of golf, walk, exercise. Business
women should stand as much as they
can, walk, pick up their own papers
instead of having the office boy do
it. There's the danger of having the
spread attributed to old age instead of
sedentary work, you know.
From what I've seen of the Fall i
silhouette a firm, even but feminine j
line will be the vogue. Exaggerated
hips won't be in the running at all.
There's consolation, though. In the S
fact that there is still ample time to j
roll the excess pads away. j
Summer is so conducive to exerrpe. j
The casual clothes, the Ioosp slacks, j
shorts, culottes, make exercise easv. j
If you are at the beach you can j
exercise, squat, jump—it's done, and j
no one thinks anything of it. j
You can lie right on thp sand, op i
i'our back for on floor or mati. hate i
the shoulders touching the floor, mat
ir sand. Arms out at shoulder level
at right angles to rest of body. Now
raise right leg and bring it over, trying
to touch the tips of the left hand. I
Repeat a few times and then try it i
left leg to right hand. I
The bark roll is one you ran do j
(good for you If you rani if you want
to attract an admiring crowd and
whittle hips down at one and the
same time. It is a little difficult for
oeginners. But. with practice cornea
finesse. Same position on back, j
shoulders touching floor, arms at sides, I
palms down. Raise both legs off the i
floor and draw them back overhead. j
5ee if you ran touch your toes to the i
floor back over your head.
This exercise does wonders for hips,
strengthens the bark, flattens the
abdomen.</text>
      </result>
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1904-06-19/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-harry-houdini</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-01-07/ed-1/?sp=43</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-09-29/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PIANO BOX FAILED FAILEDTO FAILEDTO
TO HOLD HOLDHOUDiNI HOLDHOUDiNIMter HOUDINI HOUDINIAlter
After flftyaeven minutes confinement confinementIn
t f In a zinclped imcaped box prepared prepared by em employe employ employes
ploye ploy of the William Knabe Kn1be Piano PianoCompany PtanoCompany PlaneCompany
Company Harry Houdini Jail breaker breakerand breakerand breakerand
and indcuff iidcuff king kln who wa waaUeci was tied band handamljt band1H1 band4i
amljt 4i 1H1 1 to a chair with a rope rop before beforeentering beforefntetn beforeentertn
entering fntetn the case reappeared rea ed on the tbestage thelitage theatae
stage at Chases Chaae last night J just 6n the thestroke thetroke thettroke
stroke troke of midnight midnightlioudioi mldnltrhtHoud101 midnightIloudlot
lioudioi went Into tbe box wearing an anImmaculate an1mmaculate anImmaculate
Immaculate stiff Uff shirt high h collar and anda
a wellpressed evening suit When he hev hewas hewas
v was as next seen hi his collar and tie were weremissing weret wererising
missing t i 5iDg hi hlB hiashirt shirt was wringing wet his histruuscr h hI hisI hisruU5era
I truuscr stuck to him and his h l face faceeh facebhOWCd
I eh bhOWCd owed wtCI plainly that he had fad been en through through1iore throUlh1l through1re
1iore 1l 1re re than he had expected Before B4 Beforeg fore foreging I j jteeing
teeing g sing to hi hY dressing dJealn room HoudinI Houdinlstated HoudinItated loudintstated
stated that fiftyseven minute mInutes wa w was the theIt1l1gest
1 It1l1gest mgest time lie had ever been confined confinedin
in any wooden box boxThe boxThe boxThe
The box waa brought on the stage staget IiItageby stageby
t by y the employee JIUlo and Houdlnis assist assistj1t 18t 18tant 1 1ant
ant j1t and thoroughly inspected by 900 900jf JOOIprsonll 300Jrsons
jf Iprsonll rsons who were compelled to take takeeats taketatB takeats
eats ats on the stage e because standing standingroim atandlnKHllm standingau
roim au rn could not be procured on any anyJloor anyror anytkor
Jloor of the th playhouse playhouseThe playhouaeThe playhouseThe
The committee on holding Houdini Houdinias
v as composed of Chairman J W Clouse ClouseI Clou
1 Iee Anderson Charles Birth Charles CharlesVollmer CharlesVoilmer
Vollmer Y nllmtr William llIIam Ziegler Earl Sanders Sandersand Sandera111 Sandersad I
and Wilt Butler Chairman douse e de dec deCJdld docided
CJdld c id id to put a few more screws screw in the thelX thebx their
lX ir and for fifteen minute his W fellow fellowmmitteemen fellowmmltteemen
4 mmitteemen straddled the case and andimvHl andIIlv and1i
imvHl IIlv 1i CI j screw 8CreW screws into the box as fast a aiwdrivers as aswdrlven asI
iwdrivers I could work worktlouoinl workt worklifluOlni
tlouoinl t 1 nualnl discovered tbe box was wa air airt air1t
11 1t t and asked that a a few small holes holesnored holeshtr holestred
nored htr 80 o a as to allow him to breath breathAt breathAt breathAt
At iu45 1o4 oclock Houdini seated him himself himselfn elf elfin
1 in n a chair cha on o the tJte platform above the theand thei
i S O and announced that he was r ready readylouse ady adyClouse adyJ
J louse and one of the theater em emi emtook
i vesf V e took twenty yard yar s of t brand nw nwe
I e half an inch in diameter and tied tiedi I IMnidini
Mnidini i 5 alinl in a way which the trickster trickster1ilinits trlckstetImits trickstertiiijts
ilinits Imits he b wa w was never bound befor beforeliairman beforc beforIjairman
c liairman Clouse and his men then thenI
I I if fd M d Houdini chair cha Ir and nd rope inside the theshowed theI
S showed everyone thut he was Iili there thereiiiitl tberei
i iiiitl lid u then prepared to put on the lid B Bi Be BeI Be BeI
i sir if J doing this he handed Houdini a astai atal ata1
stai tal card written by a skeptical in iniiKtual inliiiual
iiKtual 11 olual who claimed Houdini had a aml aI aS
S tS ml iOlo I assisting aamUft him At 1100 Houdlnis Houdlnisi
i I plush IU5 spook house was placed placedfr placedfr
I 5 fr f the box This being done the the or orI ortra orplSYed
I atra tra played at a a furious rate and the theiti theliUtne thesettied
iti liUtne Jien e settled down to wait waitJiut waitJt
Jiut as the hands of the stage clock clockjointed clocklinted clock1Inted I
jointed to midnight Houdini jumped jumpeddown jumpedoft
down oft the platform His HI appearance appearanceindicated appearanceindicated appearancelnhcated
indicated that he had a strenuous time timeiusi timethe I
iusi 1l1SIIIe le the case Hi H His arms were scarred scarredny
hy b ny the rope and nd there were blisters on oni onSis
tis i Sis is hands hand Houdini handed the postal postalt
t Mr Close took his hi coat from the thephuiorm theJII1ttorm
phuiorm 11 1 LI Oflfl and andleft led the stage He reap
l pired ired a moment later and assisted the
Knane j nlbe employee in removing the cover coverl c cwertu ver verto
l to tf thft that the box was empty
Houdini congratulated ihe manufac
titer tl ter l of the box box and said it was one oneof onef onet1
of f the th hardest Jobs he had ever under underIt undertlkfn underttkfl
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1907-09-01/ed-1/?sp=36</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-09-23/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WIZARD TOYS
WITH POLICE
HOUDINI HAS FUN AT JAILERS
EXPENSE
EASILY GETS OUT OF THEIR
HANDCUFFS
Man Who Releases Himself from
Crushing Weight of Manacles
Defeats Cleverest Men
on the Force
Houdlnl again baf
fled the police and of
ficers and escaped
from their most dif
ficult "hardware" last
night at the Orphe
um. Officers Gardner
and La Niece, assist
ed by Jailer Gllpln,
fastened nearly one
hundred and twenty
pounds of shackles
and handcuffs on the
wrists and ankles of
the "handcuff king,"
from which it took
him exactly eight and
one-half minutes to
escape.
This is the second
attempt made by
these three officers to
defeat Houdlni. On
Saturday evening they
handcuffed his hands
behind his back and
drew the chains of the
leg Irons through the
iandcuff chains. In this difficult posi
tion, which compelled him to crouch upon
his knees, it took Houdinl fifteen min
utes to release himself.
Gardner, La Niece and Gllpin say that
they are not through with Houdini. and
Houdlni says that if it gives them pleas
ure to shackle him they are welcome
every evening. He offered one of the
trio a year's salary— Houdlni' s, not the
officer's— to repeat one of the simplest
of his tricks which the rtflcer had boast
ed of doing. Up to date the offer has
not been accepted.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-09-29/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CROWD HAS
WILD THRILLS
HANDCUFFED MAN LEAPS INTO
THE LAKE
REMAINS BENEATH WATER AN
INTERMINABLE TIME
Harry Houdini Gives Throng of Spec
tators In Westlake Park Two
Minutes of Suspense While
Submerged
Five thousand spectators held their
breath in sympathy with Harry Hou
dini at Westlake park yesterday after
noon when the handcuff marvel did a
Count of Monte Crlsto stunt by leaping
into the lake heavily manacled.
"OOoo! I bet he's drowned," said a
small boy in awed and shuddery tones
when the man remained what seemed
an interminable time beneath the shim
mering water of the lake.
A small line of bubbles came to the
surface. Then larger bubbles arose
and a little cloud of mud drifted to tho
top. Five thousand shivers ran down
5000 spines.
"Oh, why doesn't he come up?" asked
a nervous old lady who had waited
HOUDINI, AS HE APPEA"ED WHEN
HE LEAPED INTO LAKE YES.
three hours for the opportunity to
worry about the fate of the misguided
youth.
"He's unlocking the shackles. Ho
will be up in a minute or two," said a
high school girl.
"Oh, dear, a minute or two Is enough
for him to drown In," was the dismal
reply.
"Aw, he's stalling," shouted an Irre
pressible urchin.
"No he's not. He has to get them
shackles off first. He can't swim with
them on." This from a bright lad with
a wire bridle on his teeth who waited
two hours and went home with an
autograph which read: "Harry Hand
cuff Houainl."
A man on the landing threw off his
coat and ran to the edge of the planks
looking intrntly into the water.
"He's going to jump," shouted the
throng.
"He's stuck In the mud. Someone
has got to rescue him," shouted a wise
guy who had seen Houdini Jump from
a bridge thirty feet high into 300 feet
of water or 300 feet high into thirty
feet of water. The crowd never got It
straight.
More bubbles. More mud. Then
Houdini canre slowly to the surface
feet first!
"I told you he'd stuck his head into
the mud." said the wise guy. Then the
feet disappeared. A second later Hou
dini's head bobbed to the surface. He
made it dramatic and shivery enough to
satisfy even the small gamin who had
half hoped to see a drowning or at least
aTthrllHuK rescue scene.
Laden with heavy chains and hand
cuffs enough to restrain the county
road gang Houdini leaped from the
roof of the pavilion at Westlake park.
His hands were shackled behind him.
TbTM biff uatrolmen attended to that
little detail. There are some members
of the force who would have liked to
have defeated the handcuff king even
beneath the water.
With no free hand to guide him in
the headlong dive the man's body shot
forward in an almost horizontal posi
tion. With an indescribable midair
kick he righted himself and made a
pretty but dangerously vertical dive.
The shutters of 800 cameras clicked In
unison and the awful suspense began.
The horror only ended when the man's
smiling face appeared above the water
of the lake.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1914-07-16/ed-1/?sp=16</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text>CROWD OF 15.000
WATCHES HOUDINI
Handcuff Expert, Shackled and
Boxed. Is Thrown Into Water
Rises in a Minute.
Fifteen thousand people in Battery
Park yesterday noon, cither saw or
tiied to sec Harry Houdini, known a?
the '?handcuff k,r.j.r." thrown into the
water from the tug J. A. McAllister.
The cro\?'d surged back aril forth
the water fronl with such force
that those in the front row alonn the
???a wall eed ab? tit mi'I, aided by po?
licemen, ri: I ack into the
park
pu-he(I into I n ''.or.
In the meantim? Houd ?vas having
all} hard t ?me .?ii\ inu a**:
nioir, picture photographers who in-
sisted upon reeling off his font di
id thai he had his 0?vn staff of
film-makeri on hand.
All these little troubles being I
tied, the newspapermen put the leg
irons and two pair of handcuff on
He ?va- then p;i: ii a pack?
ing box, the cover was nailed down and
boui ?tl steel tape, the whiatli
the tugboat end the "P. D, 7" I
rerboard ?vent the box, Houdini
and -dl.
In about one minute he appeared al
the surface. He had done it once be?
fore a-id had lived to hear the crowds
cheer him The spectator
r ting, some sr.ying that he k.-pt
the ke; s h ick hair, other? thai
art genius.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1914-07-16/ed-1/?sp=16</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1916-04-18/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Houdini to Be Hanged
In Strait jacket at High
Noon Here Tomorrow
"Handcuff King" to Dangle 100
Feet In Air Before Crowds
At 12:30 o'clock.
WILL .EXTRICATE HIMSELF
Expert Knot Tiers Will Superin
tend Exhibition, to Which All
Are Invited.
Harry Houdlnl has heen cordcmned)
to be hanged! i
Ho will bo hanged at 12:30 tomorrow
In front of the Munsoy building In plain
view of all of tho thousands of Wash
lngtnr.tanu who can gather on Pennsyl
vania, avenuo.
The "Handcuff King" has escaped
from ovciythlng tho pollco or saVty
llrst artists of all sorts havo designed
to confine a vicious criminal and now
ho will reach tho end of hit rope!
Tho end of tho rope will danglo 100
feet In mldnlr from the front of tho.
Munsey building -and Houdlnl will bol
attached to it by tho feet with, all tho
Ingenious knots the police or anybody
elan can devise
Arms To Bo Rigid. I
Ho wil also havo his arms securely I
bourn, to his body and his body made
rigid with the most approved type of
straltjacket. All of these things will
be done to Insure the thorough hanging
of tint worker of magic.
And Houdlnl doclarea he will hang
only long enough to loose himself from
His lncumorances!
He laughs at tho proposition to hang
him. and declares those In charge of
the operation can go as far as they
like. He guarantees that he will free
himself. And It Is agreed that he shall
go fieo If ho docs get loose.
Tho rrocidura to be followed will bo
to confine Houdini in a regulation
straltjacket. A Jacket and two
husky attendants have been secured.
The men are experienced In restraining
dai.gcioiudy Insane patients. They havo
been instructed to use the most ap
proved Jacket a tvpo from which no
escape has ever been recorded.
Houdini hasn't seer, the Jacket that
vlll bo used apd will not see it until
they put It on him The two attendants
will see to It that tho "Handcuff King"
Is placid in tho Jacket In a way they
havo of putting men in Jicketa of the
samo kind for keeps. They state they
will put Houdlnl in the jirket for keeps,
as no ono they havo over put into one
of them has ever gotten out.
In Air 100 Feet.
Then a rone will bo nttached tn Hon.
dlnl's fet so that It will not come oil
ana tacKlo will bo attached to this
rope with which Houdlnl will be hoist
ed up about 100 feet and will dangle,
head down for
The exact length of time he will dan
gle Is all up to Houdlnl. Tho men
In charge will do It so well that they
Insist he will dangle until they let
him down. Houdini thinks otherwise.
He claim ho will be thero long enough
for an average person to wriggle an
oyellu about three times in deliberate
succession.
Ho wants Just a minute or two and
then ho claims he will free himself,
throw off the straltjacket and when
he wave his arms, tho tackle men
aro to let htm down.
Put he will not be lowered until ho
hns relvnecd himself ibsolutely from
thn straltjacket.
Tho tltnn Ih M-30 tomorrow.
Thu pluca Is In front of the Jlumey
building.
r.veniody In Washington Is Invited
to cheer Houdlnl or thu policemen
and nsylum attendants who think ho
can't get nway.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1918-01-06/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>LINK NOT WORKING</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-12-28/ed-1/?sp=34</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>LINK NOT WORKING</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.
T1IK BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COM?
PLETED AND IN OPERATION.
A BRI0I1TI.T UOIITED Tl NNW. AFKfU'.PlN?: RAPID
TRANSIT FOR BLECTRIO CARS CONORS
TIO? OV TUB BTREET9 RELIEVBD,
The subway for streetcars In Boston, a pari
of whli h has Ju il b >a op? n? -i for at rvlce. is an
em.???? of more than local Interest The ne
eesslty for some relief t? the i rowded thorough?
fares above it can besl be appre? lat? d, of course,
by H lonlans; but tl?.- Modem Aib.n.s is i?; no
means th.ily cltj In this countr) which is
beset with problems of the same character.
ThofO who :ii" familiar v.iih "!h lay of tiie
land" in Bosl n remember thai Tremont-st. runs
In a ajenerall) north-and-aonth direction and
forms ihe istern boundary of th.- Common.
Ii i-; intersected by Rovlston-st., which consti?
tutes Ihe southern boundary of thai historic
parle On the Boylsl m and Tremonl st edges
of the Common there is a broad promenade.
known as the Mall. The main part of the sub?
ira. li. h Is w Id nough to a? commodate four
tracks, passes under ihe Tremonl st. Mall, and.
niter passing under Park-st, which lies along
the northern side if ine Common, extends mr
will extend, when completed) to Scollay ?Square,
thence eastward to Adams Square, ami finally
up northward again to Hayraarkel Square.
This terminus Is close to the great union rail?
way station .it the North End.
Ft en th.- oin, r of Tri mont and Boylston sts.
there are two extensions, wldn enough f>?r only
a double track. Boylston st. Mall for about '.k"> feet, and then
ascends an Incline through an op? n ul for ,'il*
feel The terminal station for this branch la
situated In th- Public Gardens. The other
branch reaches away to the southward, and. on
nearlng th Junction of Bhawmul ave. and Tn
mont-st., forks. A separate two-track incline
leads up into each of those streeta
Including th? Inclines, ihe subway has a total
length of about a mile and a half, und will con?
tain about five miles of track Al present the
branches from th.rn.-r of Boylston and Tre?
monl Bl.-. and th-- main line up to Park-Si. an
In operation. A great l-.il o? work has already
been done on the northern portion of the route,
arid it is h? i I thai everything all) be finished
within th> n \t eight months. Hi und wats
broken for the subway in April, 1805, twenty
Bine month- ago.
The depth of this underground passageway Is
1 I f. t. The Width IS L'i feel for I WO T.|. l(S, .11,d
18 feel f.-r f? ur. Al Int rvala of sis r- et, along the
side.-, si--. I posts are b t up on at.1 foundatl nB,
and from the tops of those on one side there
r? rn h a? n i to the top ..f o, i th? r
stul roof beams. Where there arc four tracks
there is a c? ntral lia.f posts in the turn I, In
addition to those along the sides, From one
ro i am t.? the n sl th? re cxl nd an ai h of
ma t.ry. These su Iv? ai hi f. mil I hi
roof, an covered with coni-rete; ind th?
mat? lal HI th? pace betWi'.-i
the Bides. A waterproof I
i In es iding from I .....a, wat r that
other? leak n fi ml ill. Th? m i
?onry floor is d, like an Inv? rted ar. h,
an l al ng II ?rural line iher? r in i a dra n At
Int? r\ ala the train a pit, from
which, whem ver the wat? r rises to a
level, the contents arc withdrawn bj auti i il
ally con troll? I 1?. :r,,- pumps
V? ntllatlon Is ff? '.-l by hui i ?l irj ran
establish? d in masonrj it thi or four
pointa along the i ne. The air Is suck l out of
the subway, and forced upward thi ugh the
op nfnga to Ihe level of ihe ?trei-i, ll u drI of
Im and? m i ctrlc imi and scores of an
Hghta ai i advanl ig? i al ?ng Ihe in
terl? r. As clectrlelt) i>d for th?
propulsion of the i ara hi? h i il
th? r.- la i. smoke lo a? umulat? i n the -Mings,
and no foul gases to offend the fa i rv?i
Tin-re is no reason why th? pla h ..-1 n I r?
main lean, sweet and bright for years.
AI th? und? rground r irse, the
subway is broaden? I A high Air? fenc? runa
lengthwise In the middle, irallng the two
noi thboui -1 tr u from the tw?i soul hi un I.
The tra- lu of e.i., t, p.ur are Ivided i rial n
gineers call an "island platform." saj feel
wide, and 300 or IfSJ feel long. Ace? i.m tie
had to on? platform from the ??(her onlj b) pro
Ing down a low flight of ita ai i through a
narrow bul brightly Illuminated pas age undei
n- ath, oi i going up i the street and rosslng
iv? r.
The cara v. hi, h run Ihn ugh the tunnel ar- oi
("..i irj li lej cars, but, iik.- many which tra-.
i other rout? In t!:-- i ty, th? y are all con?
trolled by one ror|ioratliin, Ihe West Knd Street
Hallway Company, to which, by the way, the
subwaj la- lieen leased by th? Tran t Commis
i neri 'iii fact partially explains some of the
pri au ?i taken al the stations. Then one
buys a ii ki t In lure h >a riling i.u or Hing a,
rhan? e to do o, are) thi ndui lor on I h? car col
lecta Ihe Ll? kets, Kill fn m th? i tatlon i lat
Is effected Ihrouul lun les, wbi b a.. >w
a person to pa In onlj ?in dh i ion.
in. id, easy stall rid d n n from Ih I reel
r? the und und statloi 'i i
more than thirty Btej In a (light Th ai
two flights for He northbound tracks, ind two
f ?r the Bouthl ?ui I The h ud of a li
i.; in loa d by a neat oni tory, gla
granite b ill lin Glazed white i?i i. i and i I? lit)
?,f whit.- paint Impart to ihe station interlora
a fresh and the r> appearance. At present t?..-
BOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE PUBLIC GARDEN.
?nly stations in use underground are at the cor
ner of Boylston and Tremont sts. ami at Park-st
A temporary loop at the latter point permits
the northbound cars to return without switch?
ing. When the subway is completed, however.
there uiii i.ther stations at Si o lay Square,
Adams Square and Hay market Square.
miy an engineer can begin to understand
th.- difficulties of an undertaking lik?- this
Count leas sewers, a ater-plpcs, gasplp? s and tele
phon? -Air.- conduits have been laid close to the
route, and Bom of ih.s,- have been bared dur?
ing the prigresa of the necessary excavation.
When ihelr position was at a higher level than
the r..of ,,f the future subway it was not neces?
sary to do ne re than lo protect them carefully
f.r the lime. Bui if the) were lower than the
roof, and higher than the Boor, the situation
was root, serious. Two great water mains, one
thirty Inches In diameter and the other forty
BOSTONS NEW SUBWAY FOUR-TRACK SUBWAY UNDER TRKMONT-ST.
Inches across, ?ere encountered at that very in
invenlent level, It became necessary to con
utru t siphons, bending down under the subway
and up agiln on the other Bide, in order to ad
ju-t these conflicts of Interest. Kor the happy
solution of all th.-:- difficulties great credit is
,'-j to th? t'ity Commission Intrusted with the
work, to their 'hlef ngli.r, and, in some meas?
ure, t. the engine, rs of the West End Company,
An Incidental l j: I mi orlant f. ature of tlie
plan of construction Is the avoidance of grade
i rossinirs. In the four-track passageway the
Iloylston-st. ears have the two inside tracks,
and the Tremont-st and Bhawmut-ave. ears use
the two outer ones in common. Accordingly,
at th" southeastern corner of the Common, the
westernmost track (southnound) is carried down
Under the two central ones, by a special one
track tunrnl which soon emerges With another
one-track tunnel carrying th>- up-track. At a
point still further south a similar plan Is pur
sued in th.- separating of the Bhawmut-ave. and
Tremont-st. cars
Tie- cipa. Ity of the subway is ninety cars
per mit,ute. Inasmui h as th" facilities thus af?
forded :ir.- Buppli mentary to th.me already af
forded on Tremont-st., and an- not a substitute
for the latter, a distinct increase In the number
of punes, as well as freedom from blockades,
bas been secured.
RJtlUYBRAVIVO POSTAI* CARDS.
i From The Boston Transcript.
An advertisement has appeared in some of the
daily papers In which a cosh payment has been
offered for uneancelled printed postal cards. It
seems that many business houses have occasion
j to have a large number of postal cards printed
to advertise some special line of goods or for
the use of some travelling man. For some rea?
son or other the conditions may change, so that
perhaps only half of the cards are use?), being
or m'.cd, Lbey can nut be used in any other way,,
j and the result is that in nine CSSSS out of ten
they are consigned to the waste basket, a? the
Government does not red. em uncancelled postal
cards an it does stamped envelopes.
A process has been discovered by which all of
the printed matter may be removed from the
card, leaving it in the same condition as when
bought at the poatofBcn. A charge of one-half
cent per card is- made for this work; or, in other
words, a man sends five hundred carda to be
"made over." The man who does the work
charges f?SO for his services, ami tin- u.?tomer
save? $1* ."?0, as the printed cards were of no uas
to him.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE BOSTON SUBWAY
SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF THE
STREET CAR PROBLEM.
Contention of Trafllc In tli? Iluny Streets
of the Uub Relieved by Underground
Trolley Lines?Tunnels Tlmt Am Light,
Clean uud Attractive.
It is now possible to cross Tromont
street, Boston, at any point opposite tho
Common and at any time of day without
loss of life or limb. Tho new subway has
brought about tho change.
It 1 s an old tradition that tho fathers of
Boston, when thoy laid out tho city, let
the. streets follow the winding cow paths.
At any rate, the streets ius thoy exist today
urc very crooked and must of them aro
very narrow. This was all right in Revo?
lutionary times, but when the city grow
miles beyond tho Common und spread it?
self out to tho south and west; when busi?
ness centered itself along tbu lower ends
of Washington and Trentont streets, and
when dozens of street car tracks usurped
tho narrow roadways, then the Bostonlans
wished their ancestors bud not stuck so
closely to the cow paths.
Probably no other city on the continent,
was ever so badly allllctcd with a conges?
tion of trnllic as tho Hub haslieon for
many yea: Some of tho most important
street ear linen skirt tho south and east,
cornets ol the Common on Boylston mid
Tremont streets. When I he chango was
made hum hoc. epov.vr to trolley, matters
grew worse. Then tho poles and the tan?
gle of overhead wires made that historic.
breathing spot look liko a pieco of dingy,
green billiard cloth which had become fray?
ed and tuttered around the edges. So after
much wrangling in tho legislature and
courts it w;ls decided tu build the subway
and put the trolley cars underground.
A large portion of the work bus already
lieen accomplished and Boston is delight?
ed with the result. The first thing a Hus?
ton man asks a visitor from Now York,
Chicago or elsewhere is:
"Been through tho subway yet'/ Let's
see?you huven't one in your place, have
you?"
It is, in fact, a triumph of engineering
anil well worth a visit. Then! arc throe
open cut.s where tho trolley curs enter the
subway. One Is out on Tremont street
whore Shawmut avenue comes in. Hero
the tracks from each of those jmorough
fares dive into the tunnel. Another is In
the Public gardens, where the cars com?
ing down Boylston street take tho under?
ground tlip. The third is at tho northerly
end of the subway, just beyond-Hay mar?
ket square and in front of the new Union
terminal railroad station into which the
Fitchburg, Hoston und Maine, Eastern
und other roads run. Theru is u. loop hern
DOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE Plin
LIC ns most of the t rolley lines inako it their
terminus, and, the subway being four
tracked, they disgorge their passengers
and take the back track up town.
Including the inclines or open onto, tho
subway has a total length of 1 miles and
will contain about live miles of track. At
present the branch down Boylston street
along the Common side and the main line
down Tremont to Park street are in oper?
ation. The Shawmut avenue branch and
tho northerly end of the main lino will be
finished within the next eight months.
Ground was broken for the subway in
April, 18115. The sum appropriated was
$7,ii(?0,000 and, wonderful to relate, tho
transit commissioners say that it is proba?
ble the cost will bo about $1,000,000 less
than that sum.
No groat difficulties have been encoun?
tered thus far in digging this big liplo In
the ground. Of course there were count?
less sewers, water pipes, gas pipes, electric
wire conduits and the like und some -III
inch water mains at an inconvenient level
proved rather hnrxl to handle, but n? un?
expected conditions arose to delay tho
work. The main trunk of the subway
runs under the wide walk or mall on tho
east side of the Common, anil when the
excavations were being made the bones of
hundreds of old Puritans were disturbed.
This raised a bowl of righteous Indigna?
tion,and the sncredness of the long forgot
burying ground was harped upon for
weeks. Hut the commissioners quieted
the reverent patriots by collecting nil tho
bones and roiuterrlng them in the holy
ground of the Common, with a nice monu?
ment to mark the spot.
The tleepest jioint of tho subway is on
Boylston street, where the south bound
t racks are laid lit) feet lielow the surface,
but the average depth is 14 feet. The tun?
nel itself is a giant bore with ribs of steel
mid casings! of cement, asphalt, concrete
and masonry. The roof is a series of
arches und the floor Is concave, with
drains at the bottom. As tho drnins are
below the level of the sewers, jilts have
been established at Intervals, and when
thev are filled with water automatic elec?
trical pumps are started, which empty
them Into tho sewers above.
Perhaps yon imagine that Boston's sub?
way is a tlark, damp, ill smelling place. It
is nothing of the sort. The entrances to
the stations aro handsome structures of
stone, with glass roofs. The only fault, to
be found with them is that thev remind
cs?blc. It makes food shortened
it i3 uahcaltb.ru! and filled with
icd by every medical r.::d culi- B
1
vegetable oil is nutritive, digest-
i
coil. Itisnu
:d with or fried
armful results.
md yoll^w tins,with
u((nM-/ililii( urc.il??
way. lladounlyby
1 PAN Y,
Montreal. ^?-?n?? _^ff* fa
you or an olo Urccinn tomi)?ft" least that
is what I thought of the first time I saw
one. Put then you go down an easy (light
of wide stone steps to n cheerful, brilliant?
ly lighted station. Everything Isdazzllug
ly white. The bricks lining the entrance
art? of glazed white porcelain, the mason?
ry arches are painted white and the iron
pillars and supports arc covered with im?
maculate white; enamel. Incandescent and
are lights Hash everywhere, and the vista
nhead through tho stretches of the subway
is far from u dingy one. It. Is about tho
cleanest und neatest holu In tho ground in
existence and no doubt will be kept so.
Already lifo tralllo on Tromont and Duyl
ston streets has been much decreased, ami
when tl;e subway is fully completed Bos?
ton foil: may get about their town with
comparative ease und safety.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOSTON'S UNUSED SUBWAY.
ft) H' VMDBnOltOVSD TBAXBITA TAILURE
j jjv oxvU x. rjtA otice.
Ij aYeople Reniie ta L'se It. Jot as Thfir Wonld
.1' the Hot la tbo Cronna Transit rropwed
J'v fbr Wew .rk Only Keren Per Cent, ef the
M Total Tronic Credited ta the flatmar The
j rreniable rnney TraDI o Lost to It Entirely
Jf Vat tba Condlllem Are nl Farorablr
BbS. Beaten Want, an Klevatrd nallraad Hon,
'sflf "H Before any farther attempt la mado to com'
i V Bait tbli eltr to the building of the proposed
jH underground system of rapid tranalt it would
H be well for every ono Interested to learn somo-
ll thing of the experience which Boston Is now
I lusTlng with Its subway. Boston's subway Is
li'H New York's proposed underground railroad In
L S miniature, excopt that It was constructed for
I H the use of the trolley car lines Instead of being
I V equipped with cars, motors, and power of Its
I H own, and mnnlnir two sets of trains one express
tf( I and one local.
The Boston subway short. That part now
jkVM tense Is less than ft mile In length, and the
KS farts which are under construction or proposed
R M Would add only about another mile to the tun
Hk wr Bet, There lr, perhaps, no finer specimen of
JlB passenger tunnel work any whero In the world,
aBfYS n ls doubtful -f anymore perfect tunnel
HtjH could Deconstructed.
B9p The tunnel runs under Tremont street, and
HHk Its extensions are to go under Cornhlll, Han
JJ. oxer street, and Washington streot, passing
i right through the denso business and shopping
districts, and thus securing every advantage
I that a road might have If It ran through Broad-
jf Tray, Fourteenth street and Twenty-third street,
i and part of Sixth avenue. And yet. In the face
j ef all these advantages, three months' experi
ence has shown that the Boston subway is not
popular, that people will not go Into It ex-
cept when they have to, and that the subway Is
lv a failure, save so far as It was a necosslty to re-
i'i Have the congestion of traffic on the street.
V XEED OF TUB BUDWAT.
A Bostonlans are proud of the subway. They
ri take strangers to see It, just as they take them
h to see Bunker IIIll Monument; make them ride
vM the length of It back and forth, and call alien
s' I tlon to all its fine foatures and then they keep
I away from it themsolves. Just as thoydofrom
if the monument. That this result ls of tntorest
I V to New Yorkers there can be no doubt. Tho
building of tbo subway growoutof a publloneed
Tfhloh was as absolute and pressing as the need
v ef this city for some addition to Its trafllo
in. facilities.
Hien, about ten years ago. the West End
oet Railway Company began to transform tho
horso car lines of Boston Into electric trot
lines the narrow streets In tho heart of
iton were already choked with tho dally rush
vehicles. Boston has to-day tho most ex
stve and comprehensive electrlo car system
the world. The added cars which wero re
red for tho now service fairly filled
i streets of the little central city
ere they were all concentrated. These
lines eorvo a suburban population of
trly a million persons, and it is possible to
;e a car for any part of the territory covered
.hoot going more thai a quarter of a mllo In
i city. Under a special act of the Lcglsla
e the Boston Transit Commission was ap
nted to devise a suitable means to relieve the
Station.
THE OrERATIVB COWTnAOT.
fader this commission tho subway wns
nned and is being built. Tho city of Boston
s for it and leases it to tho West End Street
llway Company for twenty years at an an
il rental which is not to be less than 4Ts per
it. upon the net cost of the tunnel, or more
,n .Ts per cent, upon tho sum of $7,000,000,
he tunnol should cost so much, and tho com
ly agrees to pay. in llou of interest, a toll of
nts for each car that passes through the
way. In caso the aggregate of tolls should
:eed the interest charges. The railroad com
ly cares for it, lights it, ventilates it, ana
ips It free from wator. i
fork was bosun on the subway on March 28,
13, and on Sept. 1 of this rear the first scc
o was put Into use. A second socllon was put
o use on Sept. 30. The main part of tbo sub
y now in use lies usdor Tremont street, bo
sen Park street and Boylst:n street. This
lion 'Is 1,700 feet long and contains four
cks. At both ends aro stations, built
nmodlously under ground and approached
m the surface by wide, easy stair
ye. wulch are protected by small or
mental stone buildings. At the BoyI
in street station the tunnel divides into
o two-tracked sections. Ono of these con
ues under Tremont street for about 1,200
it, whon its comes to tho surfaco and empties
cars upon the tracks in Tremont street and
awmut avenue, which hero diverge. The
ler branch turns sharply to the wostward,
asunder the edge of tho famous Common, to
Public Oarden beyond Ohnrles street, where
comes to tho surfaco, 1,200 foet from the
ylston streot station, and its cars goon tholr
y down Boylston street,
man standahd or coxsTitucnos.
The tunnel Is kept almost as light as day
im end to end. At the stations It ls lined on
sides with enamelled white brick. Through
t its length and on tho codings at tho
itlons It Is pnlnted white. At tlio su
ns and through the tunnol electric
hts aro hung In abundance, and to make
re that these shall not all fall at any ono tlnio
5y are divided nnd fed by two scparato clr
Its of wire, resides these lights, fixed In the
itnel, are the lights In tho passing cars, which
kept lit In making the tunnel passage. As
oorthreocarsaro passing In each direction
ery minute almost all the tliuo, their lights
me would keep it fairly well illuminated.
People doclare that they found the tunnel ro
ishlngly cool during the warm woather In Sep
nber Just after it was oponed, and In cold
lather they find It warm. No winds penetrato
and the moraont a porson gets to tho stairs at
itatlon he Is out of rench of storms. Only ono
jrce of discomfort has yet developed In tho
e of the tunnel, and that. It U belloved,
11 be remedied. This was, for the tlmo
lasted, a very groat trouble. It occurred
it month, when there had been a sudden
ange of 25 or 30 degrees in temperature,
oweathorhad been cold for thrco or four
ys, and the ground and tho Inside of tho tun
Ibadgotchillod until It was pretty nenrly as
Id under ground as on the surface. Thcncume
isoln tlio general teniperaturo of 23 or 30
grees. Tbo warm air. drawn Into tho tunnol
the ventllnting fans, struck against the
lllod roof and sides, and Immediately every
log began to weep. The cold roof and sides of
e tunnel condensed tho moisture In the
irraer air, and In a short tlmo the
jole Interior glistened with molsturu.
the stations tho condition was worst nnd pro
ced much discomfort. Here the air entered,
dof course gavo tin the greater part of its
ilsture. Most of tho moisture collected on tho
ling nnd dripped dnujion thn waiting passen
rs. People who had loft pleasant neathar
stairs found themselves exposed to trick
m streams below. It wns so bad that tbo
llroad company sot men to work scrnp
K down the roofs and Bides with riihbcr
urezers to gut rid of tho moisture. Even
this troiiblo cannot bo cured, tbo mil
sd officials do not believe that It would prove
serious consequence, bcciuso thero aro not
aro than thrco or four duj s In a year when
angrs of tetnpernturo uro wldo enough to
oduco tho drip.
REFL'SALOr THE run MO TO I'BK IT.
rho portion of (ho Bubnnyi use nt tlio pros
tllmo Is open fortrnvel from OoYlocl; A. M.
12 midnight cturlni; cwli day of tlio Muck.
lorenro at present 1,302 trips per duy being
n through ttio subway.
Vet hero Is the Bignilleaut fact; n study of tint
lly travel In tho Hiibnn-.. hour by hour and
y by day for months, Khiincd conclusive!)-, In
o judgment or tho,o who arc mont closely cou
nted, that the sub.va) U nut piipulnr.nm! that
Vf porsons tuo It, except w hen thev hnotn.
'esldcnt Littlo declares that this is aiiuuli
oro serious mutter than It would upniar to tliu
Initiated,
j THE KAKOV TIIAKKIO AVOIIIH IT,
B "In tho rush hours," he said, recently, In ills
jBA cussing tho matter, "I hit people in list tnke
HI every means of coiio)nnco that I here is at
t I hand. In these hours they Dock Into tlio sub-
Fii way as freely us they do In tliu ears i mining on
K, the surface, and during these hours nn carry
eH'-l about as many In the subway as It U possible
tJi for us to handle Iheront tboprnsotit time,"
Mf Then Mr. Little made a ntntument of which
iKmt. every street railway must reioi;nUo the truth,
lyK'l!, and which should bo inrrfiilly lonn.dered by
I M I.', every capitalist who maybe Invited to becomo
H I interested in building and operating the pio-
IbH posed rapid transit line In this city, provided tho
scheme ever gets so far as inviting contracts,
Thlsrushbourtraftlc,"Mr.Llttlocontlnued,
HkLSF "Is, however, not the business which wo mako
mv' tar money out of. If we had nothing but this
ntmi y other strlotly business traffic, it would
m
UK
b?id.1l!!,eH!.tA?i1B,lko Win business. Boring
nil tho middle part of earn day wo should bo
iu'inlf.,lSttsri!w "na (rotting nothing for
doing It. The fancy trnfUo 1s what wo want
and rely upon tho poople who ride bocauso Itls
V..VH nt to o, not bocauso they have to.
M? nTa. lhe People, our statistics show, who
will not go Into tho.subway. Wo know Just
how mnny persona tako tho cars In thn subwar.
becnuso wo sell tickets there beforo the peoplo
go upon tho station platforms, and these tickets
nro i-pllectcrl In tliocnrs. The sales of subway
car tlckcta show that thn tunnol gets a fixed
portion of the general trafllo, but docs not get Us
share of tho fluctuations,
Dlfll.tKK OF TIIF. 8UIIWAY IK ntiUItKS.
Wo carry nearly 200,000.000 pass-liners
every yoar. In September wo tarried 18.310,
(MX) passengers. Tho loop to tho Public Garden
from tho Park streot station was tho only ono
inon through tho subway during that month.
Tho atibwny trrtvel then wan 0.0 per cent, of
our wholo travel. In November, with tho Tre
mont streot and Shnwmul avenue toop open,
theMilnvnytraUIo reached 7.1 per cent, of tho
vtliolo,
"Sw His ft curious fact that although our
total number of passengers was Increased 111
October by 238,000 over the September figures,
tho number carried In tho subway was Increased
by only 7.000. Thfct great general tncronse was
nlmo-it entirely marto up of tho sort of fancy
riding 1 spoko of. Theio aro the peoplo who
Jump on n car nnd rldo downtown, ostensibly
to buy a spool of thrond or a skein of silk or
ynrn. hut really bocauso tho car Is handy and
the rldo pleasant. Theso pooplo won't go Into
the subway. If for no othor reason than becnuso
thoy won't walk down tho stairs.
"Tho steady trafllo which the tables show wo
can count upon ls shown In this table of a day's
sales of tickets on Oct. 1,"
Mr. Llttlo produced this tablet
rABSENOEns CARRIED IN BCBWAY OCT. 1, 1B07.
lloun. four.
a. M. r.
Oto 7. ill 7 4 to B S,0(IB
7 to t !A oto fl 3,408
8 to 0 S14 A to 7 l.nil
UtolO otlU 7 to S OIH
10 to 11 870 Hto V 096
11 to II! l.OUfi Oto'.O DID
r, M. lOtoll 44",
ito i l.nnintou: 247
1 to S I.K25
Oto 3 1,090 Total IS.SU7
ato 4 l.Kocl
AVOIDED EVEN MOKE IN STORMY WEATIIER.
One thing to be seen from theso Ilguros," Mr.
Llttlo added, Is that tho sulmny, although It
runs pistn number of the principal theatres,
does not get any appreciable quantiij- of that
strictly fancy riding, tho people going homo
from tbo theatres, any more than It gets the
sboppors.
On rainy days ono would suppose that tho
subway would get n bigger proportion of trafllo
than in flno weather; but this ls not true. I
mot Mr. Dalton. ono of tho Transit Commission,
the other day when It wns mining, at tho en
trance to tho Park street station.
'"Isn't this chnrnilngl' he exclaimed as he
got In out of the storm.
"I admitted th-it It was; but when I camoto
look over tha tables of daily receipts and com
pare thom with the total tralllo I found that
although tho general trafllo had fallen off less
than 0 per cent, because of tbo rainy dny, tho
subway traffic had lost 30 per cent. This Is the
rooro significant from tho fact that one
half the former number of cars nro now oft tho
streets above."
A reference to tho dally tablos showed how
tho travel In the subway fell off In unpleasant
weather. On Nor. 2, when tho usual dally
Irrffllc was 22,000 or 23,000 persons, only
14.000 went through tho subway. On Nov. 2a
tho number roll to 13,000, while tho next dny It
roso to 24,000. On Sundays, when tho tratllc
on nil parts of tho system ls fancy riding prin
cipally, tho number of passongers who go
through tbo subway falls as low as 0,000.
FACT8 FOR NEW YORK TO 1-0NDER,
These aro tho facta. If It wcro possible to
build tbo long tunnel proposed for this city nnd
mal.o all parts of It ns perfect ns tho Boston
subway, which is at least doubtful, what would
be thn effect of an oqual Indisposition of Now
Yorkers to using it upon tho chances of Its pay
ing I Tho proposed road would have enough to
contend with through tho location of its main
linos out of tho way of tho short-ride local
business, out of which alone profit ls to
be made; but If the fancy traffic avoided It, ns
It avoids the lloston subway, tho result would
bo ruinous, Tho contractors would find them
selves with no ono to carry except tho people
who wanted to ride to Harlem and far above
or to Klngsbrldge, all for fire cents, and. what
ever forfeit they had to make, they would soon
abandon tho lino for thn city to operate at a loss.
CACHES OF rUPLIC PREJUDICE.
Why the peoplo avoid tho subway Is a ques
tion much discussed. Perhaps as good nn ex
planation ns anr Is to bo found in a conversa
tion which took place between Tun Sun re
porter who gathered these fncts nnd the pretty
lrl who Owns the news stnnd at one of Boston's
est hotels.
"Ilavo you beon through the subway yet I"
ho asked enthusiastically.
"Yes," the reporter nnswored.
"I have just been through It, Isn't It grand!"
she exclaimed.
"l)o you go through it of ten I" asked tho re
porter curiously.
"Ob, no!" Bho answered. "I think It's beau
tiful, so light, and dry, and comfort bio: but I
always take a surfaco car. I think I hate to
walk up the stairs, although I am not lazy. I
walk clear out to ltoxbury and back almost
ever' day, and have lost slxteon pounds by
doing so, but, somehow, I don't llko to go up and
down stairs In tho subway."
It ls probably something more than this thnt
deters people from going underground even In a
tunnel bo well lighted. It is well known thnt
the underground roads In London do not pay,
nnd this ls duo largely to tho lack of tho fnncy
trafflc, such as overflows surface lines and ele
vated roads In New York. Ask a Londoner If
he uses tho underground roads in his own city
much, and IiIb answer Is almost suro to bo:
"Oh, yes, but only when lhavo to."
NOW BOSTON WANTS AN ELEVATED ROAD.
That Boston has awakened to the fact that
subways arc not n good thing whero they can be
avoided. Is clear from the character of tho very
latest move now on foot there. This ls to build
elevated railroads from tho ends of the subway,
nnd thus, in thoopen air, enrry tho cars out be
yond the thickly built-UD sections to Rnx
bury, Cambridge, Cbarlestown, and be
jond. This plan ls to be carried out ns
soon as tho Stato Railroad Commission agrees
to a lease of the West End road's lines to the
new elevated railroad company.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/?sp=42</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-05-08/ed-1/?sp=57</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060004/1905-01-19/ed-1/?sp=4</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ANOTHER BOSTON SUBWAY
Eat Ilpnlon Tunnel Junt Openti
IllliiM Under Itnrbor
Boston the pioneer city of America
In subway construction now boasts a
subway Maid to be the greatest single
boring yet completed under the enter
of a river or harbor It Is tho EnSt
Boston tiinnl extending from tile
zing UA8T JtOSTON TUNNEL
city proper under the harbor to
Maverick square East Boston It Is
the second subway to be opened In
Boston wns begun In 1000 has cost
3000000 and has Just been turned
over to tint Boston EIu rated Rallwny
company for operation It Id about
one ones twofifth miles In length and
has an exterior diameter of nearly
thirty feet thoilgli the thickness of
the walls bring Its Interior diameter
down to about twentyfour feet
The East Boston tunnel nets to n
depth of more than ninety feet below
tho waters of Boston harbor through
n blue day sediment It Is fov the
use of regulntlpn trolley cars which
come to the surface at the suburban
end of tilt passage nnd continue their
Journeys over tliestrce trucks Kven
trashy the tuba Vlll be connected di
rectly with the present Ruiwny In Ba
tons congested dlflUlct</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1912-06-07/ed-1/?sp=30</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOSTON'S SUBWAY, SURFACE AND ELEVATED LINES
PRACTICALLY TIED UP BY STRIKE
Boston, June 7. By noon to
day the surface, elevated and sub
way car system of Boston and
suburbs was utterly disorganized.
A strike of the union employes
of the Boston Elevated, which
controls the surface and subway
lines, was called at 4:15 o'clock
this morning after a stormy three
hour session at union headquar
ters. The elevated officials laughed
at the strike. When the union was
formed only a few weeks ago the
elevated set about a counter or
ganization, a "protective" asso
ciation they called it.
This morning the officials of
the company claimed they had
2,000 men in this protective asso
ciation who would continue to
work, and that they had 1,500
strike-breakers already imported
from New York and Philadelphia.
There was a good deal of riot
ing after the strike was called.
Cars wer.e stoned, trolleys discon
nected, motormen and conductors
who refused to recognize the
strike order roughly handled,
le,epers were put on the tracks,
and cautious Bostonians walked
to work this morning.
But the rioting never became
very serious and it was not neces
sary. As the forenoon wore on
motormen after motormen, and
conductor after conductor left
their 'packed cars standing'in the
street and went to union head
quarters to report.
Even wherfe they did not leave
the cars there always was some
one to disconnect the trolley
wires. Then the motormen and
conductors would refuse to get
off to fix it, and the police would
have to do it.
Because the guards at the
Park street terminal of the Cam-
bridge subway reported to the
union the escalators were stopped
and passengers had to climb three
flights of stairs to the street.
There are 3,800 members of the
union. The strike was called be
cause
The company refused to recog
nize the union; announced it
would employ no union .men.
When complaints were made
against men, they were laid off
without pay pending a hearing.
If exonerated and reinstated,
the pay they lost never was made
up. i
Conductors were forced to fur
nish $10 change for each trip.
Despite the company's refusal
of an increase because their
"finances wquld not stand it,"
the "loyal federation or protec
tive asspciation" members' pay
was increased when the union
was formed.
Police Commissioner O'Meara
ordered all the reserves on duty
at the subway and elevated, sta
tions and car barns this forenoon.
There already have been fifty arm
rests, but all the cases were con
tinued until oMnday.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
